Let's talk about one of the biggest
problem with wipe coding today that in
my opinion is lack of specifications not
the ability of coding agents that we
have today. I think they're pretty
decent. You see when you provide a very
simple text prompt to your coding agent
whether it's cursor codec cli code
gemini cla they have to make a lot of
assumption on your behalf which leads to
errors. Instead, you want to have a very
clear description of the features that
you want to implement along with a
highly detailed technical plan that will
also include the text stack that you
want to use, different features that you
want to have, essentially a product
requirements document. And then you want
to divide that into manageable tasks
that the coding agent can either do in
parallel or do them sequentially. So
this brings us to specsdriven
development. Now we have seen quite a
few different implementations. So for
example, Kirro from AWS is a good
example of this. The problem with Kiru
is that it can be extremely expensive.
But now GitHub came up with their own
spec kit. The beauty of this is that you
can use it with your existing coding
agents. In this video, we're going to
look at how to set it up, what are the
different capabilities, and also we're
going to talk about when not to use
this. So let's get started. Okay. So, in
order to use this specification kit, we
need to follow a fourstep process. In
the first step, we're going to specify
what exactly we want to build. So, this
is going to be a simple text
description. Here, the focus is going to
be what and why, not on the text tag
that you want to use. Next, we have the
uh slash plan. In this step, we are
going to define all the technical
details. What the architecture is going
to look like and what are the text stack
that we want to use. And don't worry,
the agent is going to actually help you
refine this. The third one is to create
individual manageable and actionable
tasks that the agent can perform. So
these are going to be the task or
feature implementation that the agent
can either implement in parallel or
sequentially. And the last step is to
use testdriven development for actual
implementation.
So all of these steps are going to be
performed as custom/comands
which this frameworks implements for
you. Now the beauty of this framework is
that you don't need to install anything
at all. All you need to do is just copy
this command, run it in the IDE or
coding agent of your choice and this is
going to download the template for you.
So let me walk you through how this
looks like. So we're going to copy this.
Okay. So we're going to just paste that
command in here. We need to change the
project name. So I'm going to call it
image nano banana. Now when you run this
command, you're going to see the
interface. Now you need to select your
coding agent. I'm using clot code. So
we're going to select that. So it's
going to download project files specific
to clot code. So in here if you see it
created another folder. So we have dot
cloud folder where you have plan specify
and tasks. These are the custom/comands
that are going to be implemented for
you. We also have memory which is used
by the agent for context management and
then scripts that are going to be run by
the agent at every step. And then we
have templates for the agent to use for
planning specification and the task that
is going to create. Now let me show you
one quick thing. So if I go back to my
terminal and if I type ls it actually
has that folder in here. So if I trigger
claude now if I type / plan we don't see
that command because we are in the root
folder right now. So for this we need to
exit. So let me go back to that folder.
And now if I trigger cloud again we
should be able to see that slash plan
command. So the first thing that you
want to do is to use /sp specify
command. Here you're going to specify
what feature you want to implement. From
what I have seen, it works with a
completely new project. I haven't really
figured out a way to implement a feature
in existing codebase. They seems to have
the capability, but I haven't seen an
easy way to do it. Okay. So I'll show
you an example project that I was trying
to implement with the spec kit. So here
I provided a simple description of a
product or project that I want to build.
We're going to be using nano banana to
create images of a person in different
style based on an uploaded image. So I
provided this quick description to GPT5
and it came up with a pretty detailed
product requirement document. Now we're
going to use parts of this because in
the first part we just want to specify
what we want and then architectural and
technical details in the planning stage.
Okay. So I basically copied the first
part that was functional and
non-functional requirements of what
exactly the app is supposed to do. So
now it's going to create specifications
based on our text description. So at
each step it keeps updating the files
that it's working with. Especially if
you look at the scripts it's going to
execute different scripts. So while the
agent is working you can see the updates
that it's making. So for example right
now it's updating this specs file that
it created for us. So based on our
initial requests here are the different
functional requirements that it updated.
In some cases it may ask you for further
clarifications. So that those are going
to be tagged as needs clarification. So
you'll have to provide more details. So
for example, you're going to see
something like this need clarification.
In this case, seems like everything is
pretty clear to the agent. So it's not
really asking for any clarifications.
Now during the planning stage, I am
going to use some of the technical
details that I collected. This also
include the API implementation. So I'm
going to ask it to use the prd.
it has information regarding how to call
the API if not then it's going to do its
own research in order to implement the
plan so this stage it's going to use
these specifications with the functional
requirements and we'll come up with a
detailed technical implementation plan
okay so in the rest of the video I'm
going to show you another project that I
have been working on because this takes
forever so for example here's this a
very similar design first during the
planning phase it does research. So it's
going to use its web search capabilities
to collect information regarding the
implementation. Then it comes up with a
design where it's going to update
multiple markdown files which basically
really documents everything that it's
going to do. Based on the design, it
came up with about 45 different tasks
that it was supposed to do. After that,
I used the /task command. The slash task
command is going to pick one or more
tasks at a time. If you use sub aents
and there are independent tasks, you can
run them in parallel. But in my case, I
had to run them sequentially. Now, every
task is marked as 001 and then 2 3 and
so on and so forth. So, depending on the
complexity of the task, it can take a
while. Okay. So finally we ended up with
59 different tasks which is a lot for an
application like this. So four of them
were related to setup then testing
integration testing. You are going to
see that it really focuses on testdriven
development which is pretty great
because it makes sure that everything
actually works. However it can be very
slow in implementation as well. So for
example, here is a set of tasks that
took about an hour and 18 minutes. Then
there was another one which took 5
minutes. I think in total it went well
over 2 hours. So for some simpler
projects, this might be way too much
time rather than just using clot code to
directly implement it. However, for more
complex projects, I think this is going
to be extremely helpful. Now the great
thing is that the agent is very
thorough. So for example, here is an
example of the data model that it came
up with and I think if you're just
starting with coding. So by reading how
it designs and define the specs, the
plan as well as the implementation
tasks, you can learn a lot from this.
And what I liked was that during the
whole design and implementation process,
it kept updating cloud.md
the way a normal human programmer would
do. So that is pretty neat that it has
support for these different coding
agents. Now that being said, it's not a
fully polished product yet because this
is the first iteration. So if you're
already coding with something like cloud
code or Gemini CLI or GitHub copilot, I
think it's definitely worth checking
out. But keep in mind that it is going
to add this additional time for
implementation of very simple projects
as well. It's still running. It's been a
couple of hours still. I haven't
finished implementation, but I'm going
to stop the recording here. Do check it
out and let me know how your experience
with this new specdriven development
toolkit is and what do you think are the
strengths and weaknesses. Anyways, I
hope you found this video useful. Thanks
for watching and as always, see you in
the next one.